78 shots & 52 cuts that changed cinema forever
78/52 is a documentary film directed by Alexandre O. Philippe.
The most famous murder scene in movie history comprises 78 camera settings
and 52 cuts: the shower scene in Alfred Hitchcock's Psycho.
78/52 tells the story of the man behind the curtain and his greatest obsession.
Marion Crane, played by Emilie Germain.
Self, played by Osgood Perkins.
Self, played by Peter Bogdanovich.
Self, played by Guillermo del Toro.
Self, played by Eli Roth.
Self, played by Jamie Lee Curtis.
78/52 is a 2017 American documentary film written and directed by Alexandre O.
The film explores themes of movie business, behind the scenes,
crime scene, special effects, violent death.
The tone is dark.